It could happen anywhere at any time.
它可能在任何时间、任何地点发生。
It's often unexpected, but almost never unappreciated.
通常出人意料，但几乎从未被忽视。
Most people, at one time or another, have been on the receiving end of a random act of kindness - that moment of pure altruism when a complete stranger stops to offer aid, generosity or compassion.
大多数人都曾或多或少地成为“随意善举”的接受者——即完全陌生的人停下脚步提供帮助、慷慨或同情的纯粹利他时刻。
You may even be in a moment of dire need.
你甚至可能正处于迫切需要帮助的时刻。
In a sometimes callous world where people can be so focused on what they're doing, a random act of kindness can make all the difference.
在这个有时冷漠的世界里，人们往往专注于自己的事情，而一个随意的善举可能会改变一切。
They can be relatively insignificant.
这些善举可能相当地微不足道。
Hannah Bailey from London, for example, told the Metro newspaper about how she was given her fruit and vegetable shopping for free. The seller did her a kindness when it emerged she didn't have any change to pay.
例如，来自伦敦的汉娜・贝利告诉《都市报》，当卖家发现她没有零钱支付时，对她十分友善，免费赠送给她本来要买的水果和蔬菜。
She was happy about it all day.
她为此开心了一整天。
The city of Naples has long had a tradition called 'caffè sospeso'.
那不勒斯市长期以来有一个名为“caffè sospeso”（待领咖啡）的传统。
When buying coffee, a person who has recently been lucky would purchase two cups but only drink one, leaving the second one anonymously, out of the goodness of their heart, for a poor person to claim for free.
买咖啡时，最近运气好的人会买两杯，只喝一杯，然后出于善意匿名留下第二杯，让穷人免费领取。
This tradition is now more common worldwide.
这一传统如今在世界范围内也越来越常见。
However, in some cases, these little acts can be a matter of life and death.
然而，在某些情况下，这些小善举可能关乎生死。
Take, for example, the unnamed commuter, who in June 2018 fell off a station platform onto an electric railway track in Toronto, Canada.
例如，2018年6月，加拿大多伦多一名未透露姓名的通勤者从站台跌落至带电的铁轨上。
A quick-thinking, but even now unknown, bystander selflessly leapt down to pull him to safety.
一位反应敏捷但至今身份不明的旁观者不顾自身安危跳下站台，将他拉到了安全地带。
Or Jonny Benjamin, who in London in 2008 was persuaded not to commit suicide by a passer-by.
再如乔尼・本杰明，2008年在伦敦被一位路人劝阻放弃自杀。
He had been considering jumping from a bridge.
他当时正考虑从桥上跳下。
He later found the Good Samaritan and thanked him.
后来他找到了那位好心人并致谢。
He may one day find a way to pay him back in kind – though that's not the point.
他也许有一天会找到一种方式回报他的善意——尽管这并非重点。
So, why do it?
那么，为什么要这样做？
Often, the acts aren't reciprocated. The people never meet again.
通常这些善举不会得到回报，人们也不再相见。
According to UK charity The Mental Health Foundation, acts like these can "give our lives new purpose, show us other perspectives on our own problems and even make us feel euphoric."
根据英国慈善机构“心理健康基金会”的说法，此类行为可以“赋予我们生活以新目标，让我们从其他角度看待自己的问题，甚至让我们感到愉悦。”
So give it a try.
所以试试看吧。
Hold open a door for someone, deliver a compliment - even give up your seat on a bus.
为别人扶门，送上一句赞美——甚至在公交车上让座。
Help someone who is in need.
帮助有需要的人。
It takes all kinds. It needn't be anything huge.
善举有很多种，不必是什么大事。
One day, whether you need it or not, someone might help you in your hour of need.
总有一天，无论你是否需要，会有人在你需要的时候帮助你。